As a ten year old, she has started writing poetry and short novels.
After attending girls' school at high school-
-Moves Karin to Uppsala to go to university.
A male -dominated environment where female students are unusual.
Karin gets her eyes on how unequal women are treated in teaching.
She had been staying in girl environments, so this with inequality-
-In how boys and girls were treated would not have been a matter for her.
Now she came to a very male -dominated environment.
One in many ways conservative environment-
-There the girls, the student shoes were something unusual.
Some thought they were intrusion into that environment.
-And now wants to start sharing their texts with more.
She gathered her best old poems and went to Bonniers publisher-
-To Karl Otto Bonnier and asked if she could be published.
After only a few weeks they heard from them and said, "Yes, you are accepted."
So she was 21 years old.
It was something very unique then.
The debut book "Cloud" is a collection of poems about a young man's pondering.
About life, about God, about his own future.
Suddenly she became a celebrity in Uppsala, a literary celebrity-
-So then she got into these author gangs.
Then she became more politically radicalized too.
With feminism she had discovered the injustices between men and women-
-and it was the next logical step to detect the injustices between class-
-and between different countries.
Interest in politics and how people in other countries had it-
-Growing with Karin and she started traveling.
Among other things, she goes to the then Soviet Union and is struck by the oppression.
1932 she travels to Berlin, the year before Hitler takes power-
-and sees how Nazism begins to permeate society-
-But then without understanding the seriousness, as for so many others.
She is curious and observes.
Fascination mixed with fear-
-What is visible in her texts.
But the trip down to Germany she not only did for the sake of travel.
Her real reason was to get help.
The suicide was a mistake, a classic cry for help that failed.
This life force has been lost.
It is important to come back to this living Karin Boye.
Yes, it hurts when buds are lacking.
Why else would spring hesitate?
Why would all our hot longing be tied in the frozen bitter pale?
After all, the casing was the bud all winter.
Texting: Elin CSisar www.btistudios.com